# Joseph M Hurd

13 McMichael Ct. • Somerdale, NJ 08083 • 609-706-5153 josephmartinhurd@gmail.com

Dear Hiring Committee,

I am a Software Developer and Software Engineering student based in the Greater Philadelphia region and I am seeking to become a member of a professional software development team. I am passionate about transforming mobile devices into tools for education, entertainment, and convenience, and I have 2-3 years of experience developing cross-platform mobile applications for iOS and Android devices.

As a student, my primary focus is on developing cross-platform mobile and desktop applications using C#, .NET, Xamarin, and Visual Studio. However, I have also studied and worked with Object Oriented Programming languages such as Java, Python, and C++, Web Development languages such as HTML and CSS, Relational Database Management languages and systems such as SQL and MySQL, and notable concepts and techniques such as Data Structures and Algorithms, Agile, and Front-end/Back-end Development. I am currently standing at 75% completion with my degree program, and I am expecting to graduate by August of 2023 with a B.S. in Software Engineering. Additionally, I have obtained certifications in CompTIA A+, CompTIA Project+, and ITIL Service Management. I am currently studying to take the AWS Cloud Practitioner certification exam.

As an independent Mobile Application Developer, my primary workflow includes but is not limited to C#, JSON, Unity, Visual Studio, Xcode, Android Studio, and Figma. My mobile applications currently serve specific userbases in the respective fields of education, entertainment, and convenience. While my apps are dedicated towards specific use cases in niche communities, they have been installed by thousands of users in over 40 countries around the world. I have converted 37% of product page viewers into users, and each app that I have published holds a 5-star rating. If you would like to view my work, you can find my live portfolio at joethehurd.io, which I am statically hosting on GitHub Pages with HTML files that I developed using WordPress on my local PHP server.

I believe that my versatility and commitment towards growth enable me to make contributions as a key member of a development team with various needs. If you feel that my background can serve as a unique and beneficial force on your team, I would love for the opportunity to discuss how I can make a positive contribution towards achieving your goals and objectives.

All of my best,

Joseph Hurd

PS – I would be glad to share with you how I improved my app's functionality and increased my conversion rate by more than 2% in less than 90 days.

# Joseph M Hurd

13 McMichael Ct. • Somerdale, NJ 08083 • 609-706-5153 josephmartinhurd@gmail.com

### **EDUCATION**

<b>Western Governors University</b> , Salt Lake City, UT Bachelor of Science, Software Engineering	2022 – Present
Rowan University, Glassboro, NJ Bachelor of Arts, History Bachelor of Arts, Secondary Education President's List, Magna Cum Laude Honors	<b>2017 – 2020</b> GPA: 3.7 GPA: 3.9
Camden County College, Blackwood, NJ Associate in Science, Secondary/Elementary Education	<b>2012 – 2017</b> GPA: 3.0

### WORK EXPERIENCE

## Mobile Application Developer, Somerdale, NJ

**2021 - Present** 

Cross-Platform Mobile Development

- Independently develop and publish mobile applications to the Google Play Console and iOS App Store using Unity, Xcode, and Android Studio.
- Program all application and UI/UX mechanics using the C# language in Visual Studio.
- Integrate 3<sup>rd</sup> party APIs to collect user metrics, manage cloud data, launch haptics, and build community leaderboards containing high scores, user statistics, and challenges.
- Implement monetization through in-app purchases and 3<sup>rd</sup> party advertisements.
- Create all music, themes, and interactive sounds using REAPER, Ableton, and Pro Tools.
- Model all application assets using Figma, Inkscape, AutoCAD, and Blender.
- Routinely perform debugging and version control, consistently optimize and upload new build packages, and utilize user data to improve application functionality and performance.

## Woodbury Junior-Senior High School, Woodbury, NJ

2020 - 2021

Social Studies Teacher of Alternative Education, Certified 6-12

- Curated and administered the Humanities curriculum for 6<sup>th</sup> through 12<sup>th</sup> grade Alternative Education students, while leading elective courses in Art Appreciation, Fundamental Math, and Business and Technology.
- Attentively participated in professional development conferences and reliably collaborated with staff and colleagues to coordinate a comprehensive effort to best meet the needs of all students.
- Served as a personal learning advocate and actively communicated with students and guardians to maintain and improve student attendance, engagement, and performance.

# Joseph M Hurd

13 McMichael Ct. • Somerdale, NJ 08083 • 609-706-5153 josephmartinhurd@gmail.com

### **WORK EXPERIENCE cont.**

### Freelance Editor, Somerdale, NJ

2017 - 2020

Editor, Mentor

- Assisted undergraduate and graduate students with the drafting, refining, and finalizing of their research papers.
- Provided valuable insights regarding students' gathering, analyzing, and interpreting of data, and guided students' research methodologies and communication techniques.

### Sylvestro Consulting, Glassboro, NJ

2014 - 2017

Draftsman, Team Leader, Instructor

- Specialized in the conceptualization of mechanical, electrical, and plumbing design for consumer-based architecture projects.
- Designed, printed, and delivered engineering-consultant drawings while also maintaining positive client relations in a competitive and professional field.
- Directed a team of three other draftsmen, taught new employees how to conceptualize within computer-aided drafting software, and designated workloads to optimize efficiency.

#### RELATED SKILLS & EXPERIENCE

Sound Design/Music Production

using REAPER, 8 years exp. using AutoCAD, 6 years exp.

• Computer-Aided Drafting

• UI/UX Design

using Figma, Inkscape, 4 years exp.

• Object-Oriented Programming

using C#, .Net Framework, 3 years exp. using Unity, Xamarin, 2 years exp.

Mobile Application Development

using Blender, 1 year exp.

3D Modeling

## **CERTIFICATIONS**

CompTIA Project+

issued by *CompTIA*, **2023** 

CompTIA A+

issued by CompTIA, 2022

ITIL Foundation Certificate in IT Service Management

issued by Axelos, 2022

### ADDITIONAL INFORMATION

Hobbies/Interests: Drumming, Kayaking, Snowboarding, Mountain Biking, Game

Development, Animal Rescue, Sociology, and the Oxford Comma

**Member**: Phi Alpha Theta National History Honor Society, Psi Iota Chapter